Quick, Quick! Minus Tempo! Back!
This position!
This timing!
This angle!
It's perfection!
CLICK!
BEEP!
CERança!
CER SAIN'
Háááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááváááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááááá.
Let's go.
I don't want to stop now
It won't be enough
I don't want to be able to do it
It's the best of the most fun things
Say Say Don't
今と今向き合って
堪能するよ現実
酸いも甘いも全部
偽不不堂々
正面取ったいらしたいな
面白そうだ
喜べそうだよな
今をやめない
味わい尽くして笑おう
ご視聴ありがとうございました
Let's go
energía
本当に
I don't understand how any of that just happened!
Right, that's our cue.
Let's go.
We messed around too much, Sumo.
I think so, Sumo. You're right.
Kageyama, did you see my sweet block?
I'm the one who stopped the ball, idiot.
Nuh-uh! That was all me, man!
Was not!
Nuh-uh!
Hello?
Crap, I got so excited, I forgot what I was gonna say!
I'm sorry for calling out of the blue. This is Anabara. And I had to talk to you.
I mean, did you?
I saw it.
It was all right.
Oh, right! Yes, of course you did. Can you believe it?
Thank you for the game!
Karasano High School earns their spot in the top 16. One of this year's favorites in Narazaki High School, led by the Mia Twins, is out after their first match.
Only day two of the Spring Nationals, but we've already seen a huge upset in this tournament.
Well, guess I'll see you later. Good game.
Uh, yeah.
Hinata!
Huh? What's up?
I promise you this. I'm gonna be sent to you one day.
Hm?
Hmm.
But before that happens...
I am gonna pound your team to dust at the Inner High, so you better be ready.
Rantings of a sore loser.
What was that?! I didn't lose! You shut your stupid mouth!
What are you doing?!
Gather round!
Nice game, you guys!
Wow!
That was the best!
You were so awesome!
Thank you so much!
If we didn't have them cheering for us,
Inarizaki would have overpowered us.
Thank you so much!
Guys!
Thank you for coming!
I am so proud to meet you, everyone of you!
Let's just get this over with.
We lost and losers don't need applause.
Shut your trap, Hatsulu!
Quit!
Huh?
That's right!
We see it on your face, but you're wrong!
You played good, dumbass!
And every good match deserves praise!
Hm!
Huh?
Grown-ups like to say it's not about the results.
It's about the process.
But you know, kids aren't like that.
I think...
You might be in the minority here, Kida.
Thank you for coming!
Inarizaki was one of the schools favored to take home the championship.
Where do you think things went wrong for your team?
I think we may have needed to lean a bit harder on our offense rather than our defense
today, and that was my mistake.
But, I have no doubt, my players made great strides in this match.
So, um...
Hm?
We...
We're very sorry.
Aren't you trying to make yourselves feel better by apologizing?
We're not doing that, okay?
Okay, okay.
My mistake.
But, if you are, make sure it's when you really feel bad for what you did.
Hm.
I have to admit it, I didn't think it was a bad idea to use that quick ride there either.
I thought it was gonna get through.
Of course...
I do hate it when you try stuff in matches that you haven't actually pulled off in practice.
Hm.
That last one was just...
matched up against the wrong two blockers.
I agree.
When the two of you really get into it,
everyone else on the court usually gets left completely behind.
But this is one of those times where...
the guy standing on the other side...
we're really into it too.
You were on a high, right?
Huh.
It's not every day that we get to have a match like that one.
Good for you.
Was Kido just smiling right there?
He was.
He actually smiled a few times while the match was going on too.
Uh-huh.
No way.
But...
It does still hurt.
Oh...
We did everything that we possibly could.
I can honestly say I have no regrets.
I haven't changed my mind either.
and I still believe the results are just a by-product.
But I don't know.
Ugh.
I wish...
I could've bragged more and said stuff like...
We made it all the way.
We'll make it happen.
We'll make sure to become the kind of underclassmen
you can brag to your grandkids about.
I cannot wait to see that.
Come on.
Let's get changed.
Tanaka.
How long have you been sitting like that?
Put your shirt on.
I don't know.
Ugh.
Suki, you've got two jackets on!
Huh?
I think this might be the first time I've seen Tsukishima about to shut down.
Did a lot of work out there today.
Makes sense.
Huh?
Nishinoya!
Don't fall asleep there!
And yet now,
the one who usually passes out first is still wide awake.
Yeah.
Hmm?
Maybe all the moving around actually made it so he can't sleep.
Today, I'm pretty sure I witnessed someone having that moment.
Day two of spring nationals.
The day this shrimp got even more hooked and fell deeper in love with volleyball.
Afternoon
Yeah!
Hey!
Kuratsuno beat the Miyas.
Come on, man.
You really didn't know?
Didn't you hear all the screaming?
I don't pay attention to what's going on outside of my match.
Anyway, Karasuno won and one of the favorites is going home now.
Oh, that sucks. I really wanted to play against those freaks.
Today, Bokuto was definitely concentrating.
He wasn't all there during our first set yesterday, but he's been in great form ever since.
No, I need to stop it.
If I keep thinking about this and start getting greedy, I have a feeling something will go wrong.
Detached. I need to remain detached.
Akashi's overthinking things again.
That was amazing! I think I might be turning into a Karasuno fan now.
So what team will they be going up against in their next match?
Nekumahai.
Hey, that's the same team that you guys had to play, isn't it?
Which of them do you think will win?
I'm not really sure, but I don't think anyone should underestimate Karasuno's momentum.
Oh, that makes sense.
I mean, Karasuno is on a roll, after all.
What do you want to do tomorrow? Should we come watch?
Yeah, okay, why not?
Did you have fun today, Mika?
Oh, yes. I can't wait for Karasuno's match tomorrow.
It can't be easy stopping that attack.
I know, right? And this Nekumah team they're up against seems sort of bland by comparison.
They're totally no match for Karasuno.
It'll be a piece of cake.
Oh, you are going to eat those words, lady!
And that concludes our story about the cat and the jealous snake.
Ha, ha, ha. It must be hard being that snake.
Ha, now moving on to sports. Over to you, Yamashita.
Here it is.
I'm here at round two of the Haruko National High School Volleyball Championship.
The seeded teams begin play for both the girls and the boys' brackets.
On the boys' side, we saw a major upset.
Ha, ha, ha.
Game two on port A was between an Arasaki High School led by the unstoppable Mia Twins
and an old contender from the Tohoku region, Karasuno High School,
a team with a heavy emphasis on offense.
They have their own all-Japan youth-intensive invitee, Tobio Kageyama.
Ah, the Mia Twins gave Karasuno some trouble with their flawless teamwork.
While the leader of Karasuno's charge was Ryunosuke Tanaka,
who may have been trying a bit too hard as he couldn't get his game done.
Ha, ha, ha. That hurts me.
Then, in the second set, Karasuno's blocker struggled to stop the quick attacks
of an Arasaki middle blocker, Rintaro Sula.
On purpose? We were doing it on purpose!
Tadashi, shut up.
Karasuno could not take the second set, but they showed remarkable tenacity in the fire.
Oh, that's me! I'm on TV!
Holy crap, your face, Suga!
Yeah, that's not a great look.
Hey, Kyoko!
Hey, they're totally giving Kyoko more screen time.
Oh, beautiful!
Hey, Sasaki!
You look like you've killed a man or two in that shot.
Man, you look rad!
Is that how I look when I concentrate?
You should see him in math class.
Look! There it is! See that? My awesome receive!
You see that, Kageyama?
Missed it.
Then look, butthead!
There's his or she!
Shut up!
So embarrassing!
This isn't like you, Bokuto.
Are you not gonna watch the news?
Hmm?
I did, remember?
I mean, I thought you'd watch it a hundred times on repeat.
Hey, what kind of person do you think I am exactly?
I wasn't on camera all that much tonight. Twenty times is more than enough.
Oh, so he's showing some restraint.
But, well, I'm still gonna be playing volleyball after high school, so I didn't think this being my last high school tournament would make it that much different from any of the others.
But man, I really wish I could play a lot more with you guys.
Huh?
You're not dying, are you, Bokuto?
What?
No!
I'm gonna live to be 130.
Then what are you talking about?
This is only day two of the tournament.
Third round, quarterfinals, then semifinals, and then finals.
We still have a lot of games ahead of us.
Yeah?
And we're gonna win them all.
Hmm.
All right, we better get inside.
It's flu and norovirus season.
You can't underestimate January.
What?
It's January?
Man.
Kageyama just gets more and more amazing.
I think I'm just gonna ask him for his autograph now.
No way that guy's come up with an autograph yet.
Not sure he can spell it.
Okay, I'll come up with one for him.
We can even finish it with a heart.
That's perfect, he'll love it.
And Tanaka played great today, too.
That cut shot?
Followed by that razor-sharp line shot.
And that rebound toward the end was insane.
He seems like the last person who could ever play so in control.
Speaking of control, what about Tsukishima?
The way he narrows down the attacker's options without even breaking a sweat?
What is he, some kind of artiste?
Yeah, I definitely would have tried to hit the ball there.
Oh, and man, then Hinata's received.
A total shocker.
That dig was something else.
But on that last point we played, when Hinata bumped Tanaka's rebound up in the air...
Yeah!
That was him, wasn't it?
It was awesome.
I totally cried.
Well, I can't blame you, but you know what?
Watching those guys grow over this last year, can't let them steal the show.
Oh, yeah, and of course, you never want to let the other team win.
But we don't want to beat ourselves, either.
Exactly.
Don't go trying to show them up with a wicked cross shot tomorrow.
What are you talking about?
You know I don't have the balls for that.
Well, you gotta get some.
Or at least lie and say you do.
Sounds like you know a lot about balls.
I am, I'm a baller.
You think so, huh?
Ooh, I know that soap.
It smells really good.
Oh, yeah?
All the girls in my class use it.
It's really nice, but I heard you're actually not supposed to wash your face and body with it too hard.
What?
But I always rub as hard as possible!
Well, I'll try to wash myself just like you do tomorrow.
Huh?
It'd be embarrassing if you watched me that closely.
You're sure full of energy today, Hinata.
I'm still excited for our match!
I want to play the next one right now!
You are a lunatic.
Come on, Tsukishima!
That wasn't sarcasm!
You meant it!
Now you're hurting my feelings!
What was that for?
You're obnoxious.
Hinata!
Your face is obnoxious!
Stalwart has always been a good word to describe Nekoma High School, but with a new high-powered middle blocker in their ranks, they're bringing both their offense and defense to new heights.
And with Karasuno building momentum, I really hope they'll at least be able to put up a good place...
Listen, jackass! Don't you try and make it sound like we're the weak ones!
Well, everyone does think that Karasuno is better than us.
What?!
Since they've beaten so many tough schools.
Screw that! We've defeated tough schools, too!
That's the whole reason we even got here!
I also see you only got a futon out for yourself!
Well, think about this. You really believe we could have beaten Ushiwaka or the Mia Twins like them?
Hey, don't just leave it at that!
I think we'll never know until we try, dude!
And while Rock may always crush scissors, it'll never be able to beat Paper!
Well, it doesn't matter what anyone thinks.
Hmm?
Because we came here specifically to play those guys and find out who's better.
As far as Kenma goes, I really don't think he'll be too bothered if they lose.
Huh?
But me? I want to win!
Wow, it's already dark?
So sorry I'm late, Akane. I got caught up in a conversation earlier.
It's okay. I just called my mom.
Uh-huh.
Oh, come on, come on, come on, come on!
Oh, come on, come on!
Oh, come on, come on, come on!
Oh, oh, oh.
I guess I finally got to have my own classic game.
So your own dumpster showdown, eh?
Hmm?
You know, for a long, long time, I really thought I knew how to teach anybody anything.
I thought that it'd be easy.
You see, son, I wanted my boys to do what I would have done, or what I wished I could
do.
And one day, I started wondering how they thought about things.
They're not me.
They're not my pawns.
Once I finally realized that obvious fact, I stopped pretending that I could teach people
and started actually teaching them.
And boy, did that ever turn out to be a tough path for me to take.
But you, you're a natural at teaching.
What?
Good thing you suck at the playing part.
Uh, what?
You think I want to do this dumpster showdown out of some sense of duty to my family?
Right now, the ones who want to beat Nekoma more than anyone else are my boys.
And let me tell you, Nekoma is not the team we had that old feud with anymore.
So please just try thinking of it as something fun this time, okay?
Nekoma is not the team we had that old feud with anymore.